Return to the magic.
Fantastic Beasts: The Secrets of Dumbledore is a fantasy,
adventure film directed by David Yates.
Professor Albus Dumbledore knows the powerful, dark wizard Gellert
Grindelwald is moving to seize control of the wizarding world.
Unable to stop him alone, he entrusts magizoologist Newt Scamander
to lead an intrepid team of wizards and witches.
They soon encounter an array of old and new beasts as they clash
with Grindelwald's growing legion of followers.
Newt Scamander, played by Eddie Redmayne.
Albus Dumbledore, played by Jude Law.
Gellert Grindelwald, played by Mads Mikkelsen.
Credence Barebone / Aurelius Dumbledore, played by Ezra Miller.
Jacob Kowalski, played by Dan Fogler.
Queenie Goldstein, played by Alison Sudol.
Fantastic Beasts: The Secrets of Dumbledore is a 2022 fantasy film
directed by David Yates from an screenplay by J.
Rowling and Steve Kloves, based on characters by Rowling.
The sequel to Fantastic Beasts: The Crimes of Grindelwald (2018), it is the third and final instalment in
the Fantastic Beasts film series and the eleventh overall in the Wizarding World franchise.
The film features an ensemble cast that includes Eddie Redmayne, Jude Law, Ezra Miller, Dan Fogler,
Alison Sudol, Callum Turner, Jessica Williams, Katherine Waterston, and Mads Mikkelsen.
Set five years after the events of its predecessor, the film sees Albus Dumbledore tasking Newt Scamander and his
allies with a mission that takes them into the heart of dark wizard Gellert Grindelwald's army.
The film was slated for release in November 2021, before it was
pushed back to April 2022 due to the COVID-19 epidemic.
Much of the main cast from the first two films
confirmed their involvement in March 2020.
Principal photography was set to begin in early 2020, but was postponed due
to the epidemic, eventually commencing in September 2020.
Johnny Depp returned as Grindelwald and filmed one scene for this film, but was asked to step down in November 2020 following
the verdict of the Depp v News Group Newspapers Ltd court case; Mads Mikkelson replaced him later that month.
Filming took place until February 2021.
Fantastic Beasts: The Secrets of Dumbledore premiered at the Royal Festival Hall in London on March 29 2022, and was
released internationally on April 14, 2022; and in the United States on April 15, by Warner Bros.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed over $407 million worldwide,
making it the lowest-grossing film in the Wizarding World franchise.
The Secrets of Dumbledore was the last film in the Wizarding World franchise for which
Stuart Craig served as production designer, before his death in 2025.
The film explores themes of prison, witch, berlin,
germany, magic, election campaign.
The tone is dark and emotional.